<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Personal Site</title>
    <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Personal Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 11:16:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tack Design Thinking</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/tack-design-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 11:16:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/tack-design-thinking/</guid>
      <description>The concept of a job application tracking helper came about for the semester project for ECSE 428 at McGill University. The purpose of the class being applying learned SW Engineering methodologies and CS concepts to design and implement a product. Because groups were made of 15 students, the basic idea of a helped got expanded to accomodate extra features. We ended up with a web app (with auth &amp;amp; inhouse job applications) and a Chrome Extension helper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fox Trot</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/fox-trot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 21:22:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/fox-trot/</guid>
      <description>Fox Trot Folding flops, cotton tops
clouds rolling past Vendôme
Tacky bridges, rusted beams
complementing Summer&amp;rsquo;s green
Neon hue, flickering light
Five red roses in the night</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wino</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/wino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 21:50:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/wino/</guid>
      <description>Say what you want about drunkenness. Pull out all the rational, healthy, moral and ethical issues around it.
But don&amp;rsquo;t do it before you&amp;rsquo;ve felt what is like to look at a simple thing that day to day life doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you the energy, time and interest to appreciate. Say for example a cloud. And have the sudden realization of why old paintings were so beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s because the clouds themselves are beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andalucía</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/andalucia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 11:22:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/andalucia/</guid>
      <description>35 minutes from Sevilla, on the road that leads to Cádiz following the Guadalquivir river, there is a medical retreat run by Carmelite nuns. The small red brick monastery has had that vocation since the Franco era. Little has changed since it&amp;rsquo;s origins, the original head nun just recently being admitted herself as a patient in the retreat due to the hiccups of age.
Agustin had been admitted 254 ago. He knew because he counted the days in the calendar of the common room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Caleta</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/caleta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 21:33:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/caleta/</guid>
      <description>Hace algunos años ocurre la siguiente historia. Puede que muchos de los hechos hayan sido embellecidos y pulidos con el paso de boca a oreja, pero la idea general y los acontecimientos principales son rotundamente reales.
Era un comando de Más o menos una docena de soldados del ejército nacional en patrulla en la selva del macizo caucano. Se toparon con una fábrica clandestina de cocaína. para los extranjeros: estas fábricas no son nada más que un par de plásticos amarrados a árboles para techo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YUL</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/yul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 21:57:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/yul/</guid>
      <description>Boeing 747, old style. Sharp cuts, straight lines, pastel colours. Air China with an old colour palette in the middle of snow storm in MTL. We were at the snow removal station for the accumulated snow in the wings. Heavy compacted snowflakes were falling relentlessly. The massive beast crossed in front of us slowly, silently. Like a moving mountain.The sound of the jet engines was muffled by the airtight windows of the aircraft giving a weird sensation to knowing the thing must be loud due to the closeness of the machine yet not hearing a single thing from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euforia</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/euforia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 21:17:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/euforia/</guid>
      <description>Euforia is To float in open waters
Drifting with the curl
Smoothly sandwiched
Between sea and sun
To jump onto a creek
Not able to see you own feet
The midnight water and skin
Not two, but one
To run under Summer rain
Soaked down to the bones
Sweet vivid heavy drops
Pouring down like champagne</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On How To Land An Airplane</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/airplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 21:43:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/airplane/</guid>
      <description>I once heard someone describe flying commercial airplanes as &amp;ldquo;hours of boredom followed by 15 seconds of sheer panic&amp;rdquo;.
I like to think about the pilot and copilot as two teenagers, with their feet up the control panel, going through their Facebook feed and Reddit. Yawning and talking shit on other pilots and stewardess while throwing paper airplanes around the cockpit.
They would suddenly go ape shit scared when the autopilot light turns off and they have to land the airplane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3757</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/3757/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 11:22:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/3757/</guid>
      <description>Somewhere up McTavish street, on an intersection I no longer remember, there is an old wooden door with generous brass bolts and a little limestone Martlet engraved on its keystone. A green rusted copper roof, exquisitely adorned with two beavers and a lys flower on each side of the door finish in what used to be a rain pipe. Nothing in the aspect of this maroon door distinguishes it from the those of the surrounding victorian houses silently clinging to the side of Mont-Royal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doña Iniesta</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/dona-iniesta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 21:14:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/dona-iniesta/</guid>
      <description>Las aguas del río Magdalena, diáfanas a la altura de la vereda, perfumaban los pastos de un olor a vainilla en la madrugada. En la época en la cual todavía se encontraban venados por esos lares, no era raro verles podando las matas de frambuesa que se apoderaron de los puentes del río. Fue tan grave la invasión de frambuesas, que la gente de la zona dejó de comer la fruta de la mamera de haber tenido que comer desayuno, almuerzo y cena de frambuesas durante toda una generación.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maritimes</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/maritimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 21:40:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/maritimes/</guid>
      <description>Maritimes Survive a drive through a starry obsidian night
And you might wake up to a fiery ruby light.
Warth will brighten up the lonely rock,
That wind and sea have cut off from this world.
Leave your blood at the salty stone dock
Then clear your wounds on its icy water pond.
Your wild animals will push you forth;
Pop your head out of the car’s window like a dog;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vik</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/vik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 21:48:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/vik/</guid>
      <description>Vik My wildest journey
Was not to be raised by the Andes’ mist,
Nor to fly through psychedelic dreams.
It was to map your satin skin,
To conquer your bare back
Across the untamed wrath
Of the Viking’s land</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>María</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/maria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 21:39:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/maria/</guid>
      <description>María María la de los ojos color canela,
Lleva la mirada baja porque se le murió su abuela.
Camina con pasos lentos,
Porque ya no hay prisa
A traves de aquellos eucaliptos
Que de pequeña le daban pa’ la gripa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laurentides</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/laurentides/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 21:37:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/laurentides/</guid>
      <description>She&amp;rsquo;d been recovering from the operation in a small health center hidden above the 45° parallel in Quebec. The road that led to the wooden cottage was solely accessible during Summer and the only other patient there was a satin white hair woman who slept through a coma. For all intentions and purposes, she was alone with the nurses who stayed one at the time on shifts of one week each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Bataille de Plataea</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/plataea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 21:29:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/plataea/</guid>
      <description>Le garçon ne devait avoir qu’une douzaine d’hivers vécus. Il marchait avec la légèreté des pas que les enfants perdent quand ils deviennent hommes. Il suivait le chemin qui flânait les pieds des montagnes de la frontière. Les envahisseurs avaient déjà franchi ces monts, il n’y avait que des prairies d’ici jusqu’à la capitale. Devant lui, après une colline, il devait trouver le bataillon ennemi et celui de la république.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep Is for the Weak</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 21:46:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/sleep/</guid>
      <description>An insomniac was sitting on his window counting how many people would walk in front of his street between moans of the couple who lived downstairs. His record was twelve on a Friday night, but this gloomy Wednesday night three was as good as he would get.
He hadn&amp;rsquo;t been able to sleep a full night since the day he saw his mother die under a snow plow crossing Sherbrooke Street back when he was young.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Patria Boba</title>
      <link>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/patria-boba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 21:35:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://camilogarcialarotta.github.io/patria-boba/</guid>
      <description>El sol de los venados se ponía bajo el pueblo del cual estaba huyendo. Descalzo, con sus rodillas raspadas por los chamizales y con su ojo derecho ya inutilizable siguió corriendo. Si su cartografía no le fallaba, iba en rumbo al sur, hacia el Orinoco. Lejos de la gente. Después pensaría a donde seguir. Por el momento sólo importaba desaparecer de esa vereda.
Apenas empezaba a bajar el ritmo cuando los oyó por primera vez.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>